Nadav Vilder

(510) 379-8530 · Berkeley, CA · nadavilder@gmail.com github.com/nadavilder · linkedin.com/in/nadavilder Authorized To Work (Green Card)

Dedicated Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience developing web applications using modern languages and frameworks. **Led the development of the Siemens Application Lifecycle Management app**, supporting Agile and diverse team collaboration. Enthusiastic about making a difference and contributing to growth in a dynamic, multicultural environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, C# (Object Oriented Programming), Java, C++
- Web Frameworks: Next.js, React.js, Node.js, jQuery, HTML, CSS
- Databases and data-centric technologies: AWS (S3), SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Apache Lucene
- Tools and Methods: Agile, Git, GitLab, Docker, CI/CD

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Polarion team, Siemens Digital Industries Software, Israel

2021 -2023

Polarion for internal teams is a unified application lifecycle management solution where you can define, build, test, and manage complex software systems. This tool serves 2,000+ developers, UX designers, QA, and PMs, increases velocity, accelerates deployments, and gives richer analytics on the entire software lifecycle

- Application Development Leadership: Led the design and implementation of a user-friendly interactive feature facilitating sprint planning for development teams, resulting in accelerated, well-organized, and highly accurate planning processes. This initiative contributed to a 50% improvement in accuracy and a 30% increase in development speed
- **Strategic Feature Engineering:** Developed and designed a user-stories prioritization feature utilizing the Weighted Shortest Job First method, with an innovative and intuitive UX that enhanced the company's ability to deliver optimal economic results
- **Cross-Org Collaboration:** Spearheaded the Siemens Startups forum, facilitating collaboration and innovative idea exchange, showcasing effective team collaboration and communication skills

Software Engineer, Google for Startups, Israel

2022

• **Empowerment App Design:** Created a prototype for a support app for women in domestic violence relationships, managing UX design and API integration with hotels, achieving a top-3 position among over 2,000 proposals

Intern Software Engineer, milab - Media Innovation Lab, Israel

2021

• Efficient Sensors Programming: Utilized advanced C++ techniques to optimize sensors and Arduino programming, improving real-time feedback in the prototype for a better user experience, highlighting fast-learning abilities

Master Sergeant, Israel Navy Submarines, Israel

2013 - 2018

- **Team Leadership & Collaboration:** Commanded a skilled team of 12 soldiers, leading high-pressure missions with excellence. Enhanced mission outcomes through strategic partnerships with Unit 8200 and other intelligence units, applying advanced technological solutions in submarine operations
- **Problem Solving:** Managed cutting-edge technologies, including advanced sensors and computer systems. Demonstrated ability to resolve technical issues, optimizing system performance for critical missions

CERTIFICATIONS

<u>Complete Web Development Bootcamp – Udemy:</u> Became a Full-Stack Web Developer <u>Python - The Practical Guide – Udemy:</u> Built my own Blockchain and Cryptocurrency

SAFe for Teams Course (5.1) – SCALED AGILE: Learned the skills to be a high-performing member of an Agile Release Train

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (BS) in Computer Science, Reichman University, Herzliya, Israel

2019 – 2022

- · Completed a hands-on web app development course, building an end-to-end E-commerce web app with Node.js and React.js
- Certification studies in data science with Scikit-Learn, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn
- Dev club: IMDb Web app, Kaggle competitions

VOLUNTEERING

Holocaust Survivors Fund: Supervised the food distribution operations for Holocaust survivors, demonstrating empathy and calm **Door2Dor:** Managed the supply chain of medical resources during COVID-19 for the elderly